okay let's begin yes okay so could you
tell me your full name please my full
name is Kong Hong uh would you like me
to spell it uh no it's fine it's fine
okay um and are you working or are you a
student I'm currently well I'm going to
become a student next year yeah I'm
working on the process of becoming well
attending a University application
process and what major did you choose uh
I think I'm going to go into pharmacy
school so like the pharmaceutical area
okay and why did you choose this
major um I chose this major because I'm
interested in the areas of biology and
chemistry and pharmacy school is a way I
can study that in depth and also I want
to be able to help um other people
through this process so I thought that
was a good major to study for that great
and what do you like doing when you have
some free time uh one of the things that
I really enjoy doing in my free time is
reading books um I read all different
kinds of books uh and I just really
enjoy it because I get to live another
person's life I can see through other
people's perspective which I think is
really valuable to me as well okay now
we're going to talk about uh your home
so what kind of housing do you live in I
currently live in an apartment um I I
think it's slightly different from other
apartments in that it's only like six
floor six floors or something um but I
think it's similar to other apartments
as well yeah and what is your favorite
room in your home my favorite room is my
bedroom just because there's a bed in it
and I sleep in the bed um so and also
it's just my place to relax whenever I
watch movies or read I do it on the bed
so it has nice memories attached to it
as well
and do you think you will live there for
a long
time uh really it's not up to me I'm
guessing it's going to be my parents and
the contract of the housing but um if it
were up to me I think yeah I would like
to live there cuz I don't like moving MH
yeah okay and what's the difference
between where you are living now and
where you have lived in the past yeah so
I have lived in different countries uh
as I was growing up one country that
I've lived in is India and India is very
different from Korea as well so just in
the um the setting and the people the
culture so that's very different as well
yeah okay now we're going to talk about
uh meeting places yeah uh so where is
your favorite place to meet your
friends uh one of my favorite places to
meet my friends though I haven't met
many is um a place called ha y I think I
really enjoy that place because there's
a lot of people a lot of restaurants
that we can hang out in but also um
there are a lot of theaters there and I
really enjoy watching musicals and uh
plays as well so by hang out there we
can we have we have access to different
kinds of theater plays restaurants
whatever that we can do making it a
great
spot yeah and do you think some places
are more suitable for meeting than
others
definitely
because
um we I meet my friends because I want
to do something with them like I want to
pursue an activity with them but if I do
if I go to places where there aren't a
lot of choices that I can or things that
I can do with my friends and it becomes
less um fun I guess to hang out with my
friends and so it's better to meet in
certain places where there are different
kinds of things we can do and different
activities that we can access
mhm and are there any differences
between your favorite favorite meeting
places now and when you were a
child yeah uh I guess the differ the
main difference would be what I was
doing in those meeting places um these
days I would again watch movies or eat
and hang out just generally with my
friends but I would imagine that when I
was younger I would go to playgrounds
perhaps with my friends to hang out um
and that in itself the the activity is
different therefore the meeting meting
place would also have to change as well
from playground to I guess popular
Street or a popular meeting place yeah
perfect all right that will do for part
one we'll go on to part two now y okay
so here is your question give you a
pencil there as well so I'll give you
one minute to take some notes okay okay
can
begin okay then that's one minute yep
okay so your question yes could you
describe an important thing that you
learned not in school or college yes um
throughout my life an important saying
that I've learned and stuck close to is
to always be grateful with what I have
and go based upon it and I learned this
when I was um moving living abroad and
so I've lived in various countries and
so I've always had to move around in
different places and because of that
I've always had a little bit of a
disconnect with my friends because I had
to move around whenever I got close I
would have to change my country and so I
would always um I through that process I
learned to be grateful to be positive um
in the current situation and I learned
it um by I guess trying to just evaluate
the situation in a more positive mindset
and look at things that I can gain from
it instead of the things that I've lost
and it's really important because gave
me a more positive outlook on life and
also it allowed me to
stay motivated to study or hang out with
my friends or meet new people instead of
dwelling on the things I've lost or the
past so yeah the saying that the saying
to be always be grateful is what I've
learned okay very
nice and who taught you this skill yeah
um I think it's I'm going to have to say
my parents
because uh I've talked to them a lot of
times when I was struggling with my
current situation for example I remember
on my first day
back I think second grade of my new
school I really struggled because I was
constantly reminded of my past school
and my past friends and I wasn't able to
really focus on the current situation
and this the present and by talking and
conversing with my parents I was able to
learn um can kind of get out of this
dark spot or the slump I guess to by
being grateful with what I have and
focusing on the positive uh parts of the
current situation rather than the
negative parts and yeah so my parents
would be the answer great really nice
okay so now we'll go on to part three of
the test
okay okay uh so yeah the first question
what can children learn from parents
uh like I said I think students well
children can learn from their parents um
their attitude in life um how they go
about living their daily life their mind
mindset as well and I guess that's one
of the many things things that they can
learn from their parents um and it's
really important to learn that from
their parents because the parents have
lived many more years than the child and
so they have gone through that process
of finding that right mindset or finding
the positive outlook um and they can
kind of pass it on to their child rather
than the child having to go through
trial and error to figure that out on
their own which is really important for
the child in their life and going
onwards and what um other influences do
children have when they're learning in
their
childhood um other than their parents I
think an important influence would be
their friends
um not just because like for example a
lot of students go to school or Academia
and in that process they meet a lot of
friends and they hang out and spend a
lot of time with them and therefore it's
inevitable that they start to I guess
adopt a lot of their mindsets uh their
way of speech or things like that and
therefore it's important to have good
friends I believe because that can
change um your course of life or that
can change your attitude which can
really alter your future as well so your
friends can also have a big influence on
you mhm yes and do you think some
children are well behaved because they
are influenced by their
parents um I guess this is a fundamental
question in the discussion of like
nature nurture I believe um part of it I
do believe because I do studied science
and biology and things like that part of
it does come from genetics and their
natural I guess body but also a lot of
it does come from their parents and
their surroundings and so that part is
the nurture aspect and so it's important
that they have a positive influence from
their parents um so that um they can
grow to be more I guess well behaved or
fitting in society yeah and how should
parents handle excuse me how should
parents handle a situation where their
children are misbehaving in
public right so I think that's a
question that a lot of parents would
struggle with um and I'm not sure I
would have the answer because I'm not a
parent but if I put myself in those the
parents shoes I think one important step
is to First tell this child that it is
not right to do this in a public setting
and I guess give them a friendly
reminder first instead of just going
straight into scolding or being mad at
them because that can start to have a
negative impact on them and they can
have um a negative outlook on the whole
situation and rather than that we can
give them something positive to focus on
say while you did while this that you
did what good I think you should do this
or kind of guide them in a certain way
instead of scolding or even hitting or
abusing your child which is really
important on the child's development as
well all right and is it necessary for
adults to learn new
things definitely um it's very important
for adults to learn new things I think
as human beings we're constantly
evolving we're constantly adopting to
new situations learning new things
and just because we're adults or past a
certain age um doesn't mean that we stop
learning or stop gaining new things from
life especially attitudes like I
mentioned but also skills or manners of
behaving in certain situations like for
example I have always been in high
school I've for four years I've been in
high school but now I'm becoming a
college student and that re requires new
skills new um things I need to learn new
attitudes and therefore I'm I'm I guess
I am an adult um technically but I'm
still growing and evolving and learning
new things which is important for any
adult as well yeah and what kind of new
things do you think elderly people
should learn elderly people so like I
think um one important thing for elderly
people to learn though I don't want to
sound cond sending in any way would be
to I guess accept or I guess go with the
flow of the modern society I think a lot
of people kind of get stuck in the past
and thinking this is how it used to be
and now we have to put that on our
children and make sure they live the
certain way as well but I think it's
important for them to learn and evaluate
the current situations the the course of
history I guess and how things are
how things are changing and kind of
adopting to that and not restricting
their student I mean restricting their
children in any way of saying you have
to stay in this tiny little box but also
allow them to um try different things as
well and so that's a new skill I guess
for them to learn okay perfect that will
do us thank you very much is that it
okay that's it all right so now let's
start with the feedback okay so I
thought it was a excellent test I think
that's definitely enough for 9.0 your
fluency pronunciation grammar uh
vocabulary all excellent all very high
level um one thing I would say in part
two right spoke for like just over a
minute okay maybe a minute and 10 minute
and 15 so in the real exam I would
always say to students uh try to keep
speaking for the full two minutes and
you you don't really need to have a
conclusion in this one but you know it's
it's in the exam it says between one to
two minutes but I would usually say just
try and keep speaking but that was great
um yeah and just I just want to point
out some like very positive things like
good Expressions I asked you one
difficult question about how should
parents handle a misbehaving student and
obviously you don't have that experience
but you said if I put myself in their
shoes in their situation so that was a
really nice expression you use some nice
um nice phrasal verbs nice idioms nice
Expressions all the way way throughout
so it was really clear really good test
so thank you for your answers thank you
so all right thank you